Ricardo Piglia Papers, 1954-2016: Finding Aid C1513
Manuscripts Division
- Series 2: Writings, 1962-2016; 14 boxes
  - Subseries 1: Drafts, 1962-2016; 12 boxes
    Includes drafts of Piglia's published and unpublished novels, short stories, and film scripts. These drafts are mostly typewritten with some handwritten annotations and corrections on loose paper or spiral bound notebooks.
    - Amalca, los hijos de Antún Nazar, 1984; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 1)
    - Amalca, los hijos de Antún Nazar - Parte II, 1984; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 2)
    - Amalca, los hijos de Antún Nazar - Parte III, 1984; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 3)
    - Blanco nocturno - "Tony Murano era...", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 4)
    - Blanco nocturno - Primera versión (Libro 1), 2008; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 5)
    - Blanco nocturno - Capítulo 1-19, 2009; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 6)
    - Blanco nocturno - Capítulo 1-19, 2009; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 7)
    - Blanco nocturno - Capítulo 1-19, 2009; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 8)
    - Blanco nocturno - Capítulo 1-20 (con epílogo), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 9)
    - Blanco nocturno - Capítulo 1-20 (con epílogo y nota), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 10)
    - Blanco nocturno - I Parte Las hermanas Belladona, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 11)
    - Blanco nocturno (pp. 149-302), 2010; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 12)
    - "Como leer un escritor" / "La lectura del escritor", 1986; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 13)
    - "De poemas", 1962-1963; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 14)
    - "Diario de un loco", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001127, Folder 15)
    - "El anillo", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 1)
    - El astillero, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 2)
    - El astillero - Primera versión (Septiembre), 1993; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 3)
    - El astillero - Primera versión (Octubre), 1993; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 4)
    - El astillero - Tercera versión, 1996; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 5)
      Collaboration with David Lipszyc.
    - El camino de Ida (2), 2013; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 6)
    - "El impenetrable", circa 2012; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 7)
    - El impostor - Primer tratamiento, 1994; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 8)
    - El impostor - Primera versión, 1994; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 9)
    - "El joyero", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 10)
    - El Laucha Benítez, 1968; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 11)
    - "El tallador", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 12)
    - "Entrevista a Jorge Luis Borges", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 13)
    - "Ficção e teoria: o escritor enquanto crítico", circa 1996; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 14)
    - "Ficción y política en la literatura argentina", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 15)
    - Foolish Heart, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 16)
    - Foolish Heart - First Draft, 1993; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 17)
    - Foolish Heart - First Draft (Spiral bound), 1993; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 18)
    - Foolish Heart - Second Draft (Spanish), 1993; 1 folder (Box B-001128, Folder 19)
    - Harbour - Second Draft, 1991-1993; 1 folder (Box B-001129, Folder 1)
    - "Historia de la edad media", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001129, Folder 2)
    - "Historia de la traducción (Arlt)" (Folder 1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001130, Folder 1)
    - "Historia de la traducción (Arlt)" (Folder 2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001130, Folder 2)
    - "Homenaje a Julio Cortázar", 1994; 1 folder (Box B-001130, Folder 3)
    - "Improvisaciones sobre un tema de Oscar Masotta (Comentario a Roberto Arlt, yo mismo)", 1999; 1 folder (Box B-001130, Folder 4)
    - La ciudad ausente - Parte I-IV, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001130, Folder 5)
    - La ciudad ausente - Parte I-IV, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001130, Folder 6)
    - La ciudad ausente - El encuentro (Photocopy), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001131, Folder 1)
    - La forma inicial: Conversaciones en Princeton, 2015; 1 folder (Box B-001131, Folder 2)
    - La hija de Tolstoi - Primera parte, 2011; 1 folder (Box B-001131, Folder 3)
    - La tia de Flanney - nueva tesis sobre el cuento, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001131, Folder 4)
    - "La investigación y el viaje", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001131, Folder 5)
    - La sonámbula - Quinta versión, 1996; 1 folder (Box B-001131, Folder 6)
    - Los casos de Croce, 2016; 1 folder (Box B-001131, Folder 7)
    - Los diarios de Emilio Renzi (II. Los años felices) (Folder 1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001131, Folder 8)
    - Los diarios de Emilio Renzi (II. Los años felices) (Folder 2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001132, Folder 1)
    - Los diarios de Emilio Renzi (III. Un día en la vida), 2015; 1 folder (Box B-001132, Folder 2)
    - "Lucía Nietzche", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001132, Folder 3)
    - "Memoria y tradición", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001132, Folder 4)
    - "Mi defensa", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001132, Folder 5)
    - Relatos: Novela "Pavese" / La loca y el relato del crimen / Nombre falso, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001132, Folder 6)
      Inscription: "Relatos: La loca y el relato del crimen. Pavese. Nombre falso."
    - Plata quemada - Research Notes and Newspaper Clippings, 1965; 1 folder (Box B-001133, Folder 1)
    - Plata quemada -Typewritten Draft on Spiralbound Notebook, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001133, Folder 2)
    - Plata quemada (Novela) -Typewritten Draft on Spiralbound Notebook, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001133, Folder 3)
    - Plata quemada - Uno-Cinco (Spiralbound Notebook, pp.1-73), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001133, Folder 4)
    - Prisión perpetua - pp. 1-53, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001133, Folder 5)
    - Prisión perpetua - Borradores (Folder 1 of 2), circa 1980s; 1 folder (Box B-001133, Folder 6)
    - Prisión perpetua - Borradores (Folder 2 of 2), circa 1980s; 1 folder (Box B-001134, Folder 1)
    - "¿Qué es un lector?" - Prueba, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001134, Folder 2)
    - Respiración artificial - Primeras versiones ("Tics, tics, tics"), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001134, Folder 3)
    - Respiración artificial - Primera/Segunda Parte, 1980; 1 folder (Box B-001134, Folder 4)
    - Respiración artificial - "La prolijidad de lo real" (Folder 1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001135, Folder 1)
    - Respiración artificial - "La prolijidad de lo real" (Folder 2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001135, Folder 2)
    - Respiración artificial I - Borradores (Folder 1 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001135, Folder 3)
    - Respiración artificial I - Borradores (Folder 2 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001135, Folder 4)
    - Respiración artificial I - Borradores (Folder 3 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001135, Folder 5)
    - Respiración artificial II - Borradores (Folder 1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001136, Folder 1)
    - Respiración artificial II - Borradores (Folder 2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001136, Folder 2)
    - Respiración artificial III - Borradores (Folder 1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001136, Folder 3)
    - Respiración artificial III - Borradores (Folder 2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001136, Folder 4)
    - "Roberto Arlt: La ficción del dinero", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001137, Folder 1)
    - Sin salida (Folder 1 of 2), 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001137, Folder 2)
    - Sin salida (Folder 2 of 2), 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001137, Folder 3)
    - "Tierna es la noche", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001137, Folder 4)
    - "Trata de blancas", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001137, Folder 5)
    - "Trata de blancas" - Facultad de Humanidades La Plata Seminario, 23 de Junio, 1988; 1 folder (Box B-001137, Folder 6)
    - "Un encuentro en Saint Nazaire (a Christian Bouthemy)", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 1)
    - Vida Serial - Primera versión (I. El accidente), circa 2013; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 2)
    - Vida Serial - Spiralbound Notebook with Loose Pages Inserted, circa 2013; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 3)
    - Vida Serial - Capítulo 1-Epílogo - Heavy Annotations, circa 2013; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 4)
    - Vida Serial - Capítulo 1-Epílogo, circa 2013; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2: Contracts and Cases, 1976-2013; 2 boxes
    Contains various publishing contracts and legal documents relating to a lawsuit Piglia was involved in for Plata quemada.
    - Contracts Relating to Work on Roberto Arlt, circa 1993; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 6)
    - Editorial Sudamericana S.A., circa 1988; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 7)
    - El último lector - Contracts, 2005; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 8)
    - Foolish Heart - Contract, 1992; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 9)
    - Formas breves - Contracts, 1999-2000; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 10)
    - Grupo Editorial Planeta - Contrato de Edición, 2003; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 11)
    - La ciudad ausente (The Absent City) - Contracts, 1999-2007; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 12)
    - Multiple Works - Espasa Calpe Contract, 1994; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 13)
    - Plata quemada - Contracts, 1998-2007; 1 folder (Box B-001138, Folder 14)
    - Plata quemada - Court Documents, 1998-2001; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 1)
      Sobre el juicio de Editorial Planeta.
    - Plata quemada - Court Documents - Mi defensa / Testigos, 2001-2005; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 2)
    - "Por el amor al arte" / "El amor enfermo" - Editorial Planeta Argentina, 2000; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 3)
    - Respiración artificial - Contract, 1998; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 4)
    - Various Contracts, 1976-2013; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3: Printed Materials, 1967-2014; 2 boxes
    Includes printed materials such as magazines and journals that feature Piglia's published articles and essays.
    - Antología personal (Fondo de Cultura Económica), 2014; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 6)
    - Magazines, 1974-1982; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 7)
    - Magazines, circa 1984-1987; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 8)
    - Magazines, 1995; 1 folder (Box B-001139, Folder 9)
    - Various Printed Materials, circa 1967-2004; 1 folder (Box B-001173, Folder 1)
- Series 3: Loose Page Notes and Drafts, 1962-1997; 24 boxes
  This series contains loose page handwritten and typewritten notes and drafts concerning reoccuring research topics in Piglia's work such as the Argentine novel, Argentine political history, Latin American literature, genre, narration, translation, and fiction, among other topics. Piglia kept extensive notes on the works of a number of Latin American literary figures such as Roberto Arlt, Jorge Luis Borges, Domingo Faustino Sarmiento, Macedonio Fernández, Leopoldo Lugones, Manuel Puig, and Juan José Saer, among others. Piglia's tendency to draw connections among multiple of his research topics and investigations is heavily reflected in these notes. The order of this material reflects, in most part, the original order the collection was received. General themes and topics were used in attempt to best describe this content; folder content will certainly overlap with other folder content and titles.
  - Subseries 1: Course Development Notes, 1968-1997; 2 boxes
    Contains loose course development notes on various topics. Many notes were kept in their original order and original folder titles in Spanish were used when available. For more complete course development notes see "Academic Career and Teaching Files" series.
    - Bibliografía básica: Problemas de la novela / La otra lengua, circa 1993; 1 folder (Box B-001140, Folder 1)
    - Clases: Sciarreta (1er año), 1968-1969; 1 folder (Box B-001140, Folder 2)
    - Curso: La ficción Argentina II - Teoría, 1985-1988; 1 folder (Box B-001140, Folder 3)
    - Curso Onetti (1 of 2), 1991-1997; 1 folder (Box B-001140, Folder 4)
    - Curso Onetti (2 of 2), 1991-1997; 1 folder (Box B-001140, Folder 5)
    - La novela argentina (1 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001140, Folder 6)
    - La novela argentina (2 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001140, Folder 7)
    - La novela argentina (3 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 1)
    - Literatura argentina después de Borges, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 2)
    - Notas de clases sobre las tres vanguardias (1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 3)
    - Notas de clases sobre las tres vanguardias (2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 4)
    - Notas sobre los adioses, Onetti, la negación, etc., 1997; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 5)
    - Notas sobre Pound-H. James / Crítica y cortesía / La narración, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 6)
    - Novela argentina II - Sarmiento / Macedonio / Arlt / Puig / Cambaceres, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 7)
    - Sarmiento (Curso II Semestre) Ideología y literatura, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 8)
    - Teoría de la novela en Walter Benjamin, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001141, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2: Drafts, 1962-1996; 8 boxes
    Mostly incomplete loose pages of articles, essays, or chapters that evolved into to larger or more complete works.
    - About Arlt: ("El escritor fracasado" / "Roberto Arlt: Una crítica de la economía literaria"/ "Ideología de la literatura" / "La ficción del dinero") (1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001142, Folder 1)
    - About Arlt: ("El escritor fracasado" / "Roberto Arlt: Una crítica de la economía literaria" / "Ideología de la literatura" / "La ficción del dinero") (2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001142, Folder 2)
    - About World War I / World War II, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001142, Folder 3)
    - "Ada o el amor" / "Ejercicio del tiro", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001142, Folder 4)
    - Blanco nocturno, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001142, Folder 5)
    - Borges (Ideología y ficción en Borges) - Primeros borradores (Folder 1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001142, Folder 6)
    - Borges (Ideología y ficción en Borges) - Primeros borradores (Folder 2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001142, Folder 7)
    - "Borges: La erudición apócrifa", circa 1971; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 1)
    - "Borges y el debate actual en la literatura argentina", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 2)
    - "Cómo está hecho el Ulises de Joyce", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 3)
    - "Cómo leer a Borges" I, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 4)
    - "Consideraciones preliminares sobre Macedonio Fernández", 1982; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 5)
    - "El arte de narrar" / "Modos de narrar", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 6)
    - "El encargo social", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 7)
    - "El exilio interior" / "El exilio exterior", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 8)
    - "El fluir de la vida", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 9)
    - "El ingeniero", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 10)
    - "El jugador de Chejov", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 11)
    - "Ficción y política en la literatura argentina", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 12)
    - Gombrowicz.1 - Introducción, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001143, Folder 13)
    - "Hipótesis para una lectura ideológica de Borges" / "Sobre Arlt y Borges: Hipótesis para un análisis de las relaciones entre ideología", circa 1971; 1 folder (Box B-001144, Folder 1)
    - "Historia de la traducción" / "Isla de Finnegans", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001144, Folder 2)
    - "Ideología y ficción en Borges", 1974-1986; 1 folder (Box B-001144, Folder 3)
    - "Köninger o la incertidumbre", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001144, Folder 4)
    - "La educación sentimental", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001144, Folder 5)
    - "La forma nouvelle" - Traducción, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001144, Folder 6)
    - "La fortaleza vacia" / "La isla" (1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001172, Folder 2)
    - "La fortaleza vacia" / "La isla" (2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001172, Folder 3)
    - "La otra escena", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001144, Folder 7)
    - "La prolijidad de lo real", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 1)
    - "La posición de Dostoievsky en la Teoría y la Historia de la Novela Moderna", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 2)
    - "Llegada. Malvinas. Locura (La ficción en la realidad)" and Other Unidentified Work, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 3)
    - "Los dos linajes", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 4)
    - "Los últimos días de Roberto Arlt" / "Lettif", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 5)
    - "Materiales sobre literatura en un diario", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 6)
    - Micro-operas and Other Performing Arts Works, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 7)
    - "Notas al margen de Adán Buenosayres" / "Analogía" (Sarmiento) / La ficción colonial (Arlt), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 8)
    - "Novela negra" / "La educación sentimental" (1 of 2), circa 1974-1975; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 9)
    - "Novela negra" / "La educación sentimental" (2 of 2), circa 1974-1975; 1 folder (Box B-001145, Folder 10)
    - "Nueva tesis sobre el cuento", 1996; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 1)
    - "Osvaldo Lamborghini, guionista de historietas", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 2)
    - "Páginas de un libro (olvidado) sobre Roberto Arlt", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 3)
    - "Páginas de un libro sobre Borges", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001172, Folder 6)
    - "Poéticas de la novela en América Latina", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 4)
    - "Primera parte en el New Deal", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 5)
    - "Ratliff o el narrador" / "La vida privada de Steve Ratliff", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 6)
    - Respiración artificial, 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 7)
    - "Roberto Arlt: Génesis de una escritura" / "Roberto Arlt: Legibilidad y apropiación", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 8)
    - "Santiago Santos, mi amigo", 1962; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 9)
    - "Sarmiento, escritor", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 10)
    - "Sarmiento, escritor" / "La mirada de Sarmiento" / "Primera página del Facundo", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 11)
    - "Teoría de la novela en Walter Benjamin", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 12)
    - "The Writer's Laboratory", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 13)
    - "Todo sucede siempre sin que uno lo pueda prevenir...", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001146, Folder 14)
    - "Traducción" (Capítulo para pasado y presente), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001147, Folder 1)
    - "Traducción como el génesis del valor", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001147, Folder 2)
    - "Traducción, literatura y dependencia", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001147, Folder 3)
    - "Traducción, literatura y dependencia" - Notes, 1971; 1 folder (Box B-001147, Folder 4)
    - "Traducción, literatura y dependencia" - Notes / Arlt el juguete rabioso, 1968; 1 folder (Box B-001147, Folder 5)
    - "Un sueño de Borges", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001147, Folder 6)
    - "Una novela que comienza" / "Otra novela que comienza", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001147, Folder 7)
    - "Una visita", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001147, Folder 8)
    - Various Loose Page Drafts, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001173, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Notes About Various Research Topics, 1971-1991; 14 boxes
    This section contains loose page notes relating to Piglia's major research topics such as the works of Roberto Arlt, Jorge Luis Borges, Macedonio Fernández, Leopoldo Lugones, Domingo Faustino Sarmiento, and Roberto Walsh. This material was heavily disorganized; general folder labels were applied.
    - Arlt y Borges / Apropiación: Referencias, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001148, Folder 1)
    - Arlt y Borges: Elementos y materiales para una historia de la literatura argentina, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box B-001148, Folder 2)
    - Arlt: La ficción del dinero / Borges Parte II: Modos de traducción, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001148, Folder 3)
    - "Borges: un escritor subdesarrollado" / El desarrollo, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001148, Folder 4)
    - Borges: Notas (Literatura y independencia), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001148, Folder 5)
    - Campo intelectual, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001149, Folder 1)
    - Crónicas inglesas, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001149, Folder 2)
    - Dos cuestiones (literatura argentina y vanguardia), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001149, Folder 3)
    - Editorial: "Pavese o la creación lúcida" / Herman Melville, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001149, Folder 4)
    - Escritos en marcha: "Borges - La muerte y la brújula" / Various notes on Borges (1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001149, Folder 5)
    - Escritos en marcha: "Borges - La muerte y la brújula" / Various notes on Borges (2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001149, Folder 6)
    - Fichas, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 1)
    - Fichas bibliográficas, circa 1989; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 2)
    - Literatura (serie / autonomía ficción novela), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 3)
    - Notas en un diario / "La isla de Finnegans", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 4)
    - Notas generales (sobre Sarmiento y otros), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 5)
    - Notas para tratar de entender a Tarufeti, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 6)
    - Notas sobre Arlt / Borges / Revolución, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 7)
    - Notas sobre Arlt / Borges / Traducción, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 8)
    - Notas sobre Arlt / Sarmiento, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001150, Folder 9)
    - Notas sobre Arlt / Estructuras / Fantástico, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001151, Folder 1)
    - Notas sobre Carlos Astrada, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001151, Folder 2)
    - Notas sobre el género / Adolfo Bioy-Casares / poéticas de la novela, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001151, Folder 3)
    - Notas sobre "El otro", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001151, Folder 4)
    - Notas sobre escritura y revolución, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001151, Folder 5)
    - Notas sobre Eugenio Cambaceres, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001151, Folder 6)
    - Notas sobre Facundo / Borges / Faulkner / Sarmiento, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001151, Folder 7)
    - Notas sobre Facundo / Traducción / La ficción colonial, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001151, Folder 8)
    - Notas sobre filosofía, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001152, Folder 1)
    - Notas sobre Gabriel García Márquez / Onetti, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001152, Folder 2)
    - Notas sobre ideología y Marx, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001152, Folder 3)
    - Notas sobre ideología / China / Mao, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001152, Folder 4)
    - Notas sobre Juan José Saer, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001152, Folder 5)
    - Notas sobre la historia argentina / Sarmiento / Rosas, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001152, Folder 6)
    - Notas sobre la historia política del siglo XIX / Sarmiento / Rosas, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001172, Folder 4)
    - Notas sobre la literatura del siglo XIX, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001152, Folder 7)
    - Notas sobre la nouvelle / Onetti, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001152, Folder 8)
    - Notas sobre la novela argentina / Sarmiento, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001153, Folder 1)
    - Notas sobre la novela / Teoría de la novela / Género, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001153, Folder 2)
    - Notas sobre la vanguardia / Las Tres Vanguardias (Manuel Puig), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001153, Folder 3)
    - Notas sobre la vanguardia / Teoría de la novela, 1989; 1 folder (Box B-001153, Folder 4)
    - Notas sobre Leopoldo Marechal, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001153, Folder 5)
    - Notas sobre literatura y revolución, 1972; 1 folder (Box B-001153, Folder 6)
    - Notas sobre lo verosímil / "El laboritorio del escritor" / Vanguardia y traducción (1 of 2), 1976-1982; 1 folder (Box B-001153, Folder 7)